了解标准的控件库是很好的  但是作为一个曾被人指责
Knowing the standard widget library is nice, but as someone who
重复造轮子
was once accused as not so much recreating the wheel, as hand
喜欢自己手动创建东西的人  我知道有的时候
machining my own nuts and bolts, I know there are times
工具箱中并没有合适的工具来完成工作
when nothing in the tool chest will quite do the job. That's
这时就需要你开始从头创建你的
when it's time to dive in and build you own custom
自定义View   我们并不会全面讲解如何创建
view from scratch. Now we're not going to be including any custom
自定义View  但是我们仍然来简单看看你可以
views within Sunshine, but we can still take a look at how
怎样做这件事  我们从创建一个新的View类开始
you would build one. We'll start by creating a new class for
我们把它命名为MyView
our view. Let's call it MyView. If
如果你不是修改一个现成的View类  而是从头开始创建
you're building something from scratch, rather than modify an
新的类  这个新的类可以继承View类
existing view, it should descend from either View
或者SurfaceView类  View提供基于Canvas画布的
itself or from SurfaceView. View offers a light
轻量级解决方案  而SurfaceView被特别设计
weight, canvas-based approach, while SurfaceView is designed
为需要快速刷新或者使用3D图像的UI元素提供支持
specifically to support UI elements that require rapid redraws
它使用类似OpenGL的技术
and/or 3D graphics, using something like OpenGL.
它最适合用来显示视频或者游戏
It's perfect for views that display video or games.
现有的控件库是完全基于View类的
Now the existing widget library is entirely view
所以我们也使用View类  默认的View
based. So let's take that approach. The base view
类会画出一个没有边界的100x100像素的空正方形区域
class draws an empty borderless 100 by 100 pixel
为了改变这个默认行为  我们可以覆写onMeasure()方法
box. To change that, we override the onMeasure handler,
这样可以指出View的大小
which allows us to indicate the view size.
我们同时覆写onDraw()方法来画出
We'll also override onDraw, in order to draw our
自定义View的内容  如果
own custom view content. Now if it turns out
你的View永远都是一个100x100像素的空正方形区域
that your view should always be an empty 100
那么你什么都不需要做  不然我们还是需要做一些
pixel box then you're in luck. Otherwise we need to do
工作的  所以我们从设置View的大小开始  onMeasure()方法
some work. So let's start by setting our view's size. onMeasure is
会在父View布局放置它的子View的时候被调用
called when your view's parent is laying out it's children. As
就如你所知  当你把一个View添加到一个布局中的时候
you know, when you add a view to a layout you can
你可以指定具体的高度和宽度  但是大多数情况
specify a specific height or width, but in most cases you'll
你会希望它填满父布局或者保持自身大小  当一个View的
want to either match parent or wrap the content. When a view's
onMeasure()方法被它的父布局调用的时候  父布局会问它需要占据
onMeasure is called by its parent layout, it asks, how much space
多大的空间  并且通过传进这些参数告知它
will you use? And passes in how much space is available, and
有多少空间是可以使用的  以及它被赋予了刚好这么多空间
whether the view will be given exactly that much
还是最多这么多空间
space, or at most that much space using these parameters.
你可以这样解析这些参数  然后你就可以获得
You can decode those parameters like this. And that'll allow
宽高标准的具体大小
you to obtain the size and the mode for your
和模式  这个例子中我们只演示
height and width specifications. In this example we're demonstrating just
怎么处理高度参数  但这也同样适用于宽度参数
for the height parameter, but it works the same for
然后我们就可以使用解析出来的模式
width. We can then use the decoded mode parameter to
来设置View的大小
find out what size we should set our view to.
如果返回的模式是EXACTLY  View会被放置进
If the returned mode is EXACTLY, the view will be placed
刚好这么大的区域  如果你得到了EXACTLY模式
into an area of exactly that size. You'll be passed that
要么就是布局指定了一个具体的大小
value if the layout has specified a specific size or if
或者View本身被要求填满父布局  在这两种情况中
the view has been asked to fill the parent. In either case,
最好是直接使用传进来的大小数值
it's best practice to simply return the value passed in, unless
除非这个数值小于你的View的最小的大小  这样的话
that value is below your views minimum size, in which case
你可以使用这个最小的大小  并根据需要让父布局
you can return the minimum value and rely on the parent
来提供裁剪或者滑动的功能  另外一种可能的模式是AT_MOST
layout to crop or scroll as necessary. Another alternative is AT_MOST. This
这是指如果你的View可以自己决定大小  那么就直接使用被赋予的
indicates that your view can define its own size, up to the
大小  这通常是被用于设置为按自身大小显示的View
size given. This is typically the case for views set to wrap
这些View应该占据刚好用来显示自身内容
content, where the view should be as wide as it needs to
的大小  但是不能超过这个大小
be to display its content, but no wider than that. And of
当然不管你怎么显示这样的View  它必须还是要受传进来的大小参数的限制
course all of that's provided that it still fits within the parent
要位于它的父布局的里面
container as indicated by the size
我们刚刚完成了
parameter. Now we've just finished calculating
高度参数的计算  你还需要对宽度参数
all of that for the height parameter and you'd need to do
做同样的计算  一旦你完成了上面的工作
exactly the same thing again for width. Once you've done that and
并确定了你控制的大小  你必须调用
determined the size of your control, you have to call
setMeasuredDimension()方法  你向这个方法传入宽度和高度的
the setMeasuredDimension method. Here you pass in your width and
数值  如果你不调用这个setMeasuredDimension()方法
height values. If you don't call this setMeasuredDimension method, your
你的应用会在View放置完后立即崩溃
app will crash as soon as your view is laid out.